artificial intelligence updates uh every
Friday at 2 p.m. Eastern. Today is
Friday, May 29th. And as you see, there
are a lot of updates. Uh let me go to
our leaderboard uh arena. So what you
see here is uh as usual uh Claude uh
Oppus is on the first place. We have
this Chinese model GLM 5.1 which is
right after Claude before Gemini before
uh Muse before everything else. So this
is uh new uh okay uh next Claude Oppus
4.8 it was released yesterday and it is
a huge huge thing. So first of all it is
better than uh Oppus 4.7 in many
benchmarks in many like parameters. Uh
also um they have same price which and
it became new default. So if you go in
any tool where you used to use Oppus 4.7
now it's OP 4.8 same price. Uh now um
they have couple features which will
increase your usage. Um one of them they
have uh so-called fast mode. So it gives
you 2.5 faster speed but at twice uh
price. So instead of 5 million per input
you will uh $5 per million uh tokens and
25 for output tokens you will pay 10 and
50. But the speed is 2 and a half times
faster. Another way you can increase
your usage by using multiple sub aents
and they have this new thing called
dynamic workflows. It's also called
ultra code. So ultra code setting by
default it's on. Uh so it can spawn up
to like thousand parallel sub aents uh
to do the task. So what cloud now can do
it can orchestrate uh given the task it
will create a workflow where multiple
agents will work in parallel to execute
the task and they have very important
features like they for example have
judges to verify that the task completed
successfully which is very very
important. So what it means that when it
does the task um you can trust it much
more so it becoming more honest like
less hallucinating less making mistakes.
So this is actually huge. You can also
have control about effort and they have
multiple levels levels of uh uh control
and so on. Uh there are so many videos
and I I put this link uh uh thank you
Sandra for sending it. Uh this is u very
good article which shows how to actually
use these features. So how to enable
massively parallel execution adversarial
verification. So when agents are in
adversarial relationship one agent does
something another uh criticizes it and
objects or whatever. Scalable test time
computer reusable automation. So this is
this is great release. Um uh Corser
composer 2.5 model.
So composer you would think it's um UI.
No no it's it's a model and uh it's
built on top of Kim K 2.5. So this is
Chinese model and it has trillion
parameters and usually in America people
don't like to use Chinese models but
here what they have done they took this
model which is open source and they
trained it and when I say they it is a
cursor cursor is a company which
provides AI enabled editor for coding
and they have a lot of data uh which for
programming for coding and they uh made
a partnership with Ellen Musk's
companies in fact
uh Ellen Musk companies uh will acquire
cursor but because they are in the
process of IPO they made a contract so
that they partner but they haven't
acquired yet they will do it after the
IPO but anyway cursor got access to huge
data centers which Ellen Musk's
companies have and they use these data
centers to train the model which was
already good LLM model to train it
specifically
uh for coding and they achieved very
good results and they provide this model
inside the cursor editor. So it is not
available by itself anywhere else. It
only available inside cursor and it is
10 times cheaper than other models on
this platform. So what they're trying to
do I guess is to promote
uh cursor. So it's called cursor
composer uh the model. Now uh
interesting about token costs. Um
enterprise start using agents more and
more and agents uh uh consume a lot of
tokens and suddenly you have costs of
tokens as high as human salaries.
Um, so if you spending uh let's say $700
running your agent uh cloth code or
whatever to do the development, multiply
it by 22 days in a month, so you have
$15,000. So it's a human salary, right?
At the same time, what's interesting
like in China decrease token price like
50 to 100 times. So you are talking
about you see 0.0036 0036 per million
tokens and they they really somehow
achieved very very low prices
and u pretty fast 57 tokens per second.
This is this is good enough. Deepseek um
when they released they gave gave a
discount like 75% discount and now they
decided to keep it to make it permanent.
So it looks like token prices go down
but at the same time token usage goes up
and it goes up faster than the price of
tokens going down. Okay. Uh so here
companies are shifting towards a hybrid
approach using frontier models for heavy
architectural planning and routing to a
cheaper models to do like simple work.
Uh same with Google uh SpaceX and so on.
Okay. uh Cahir command A+ was open
sourced. So Kahir is a company which
produces models and systems for
enterprise and they also took uh their
model and uh it's a 218 billion
parameter model and they made it open
source. It runs on just two H100 GPUs.
Uh coding today is mostly done by AI.
Well, I didn't touch code. I'm coding
every day, but I didn't touch code with
my hands for probably half a year. Uh,
Google says 75 of this new code is AI
generated. Entropic 90%. Meta now
mandated 75 for most of their code.
Amazon rolled out cloud code for every
corporate employee. Uh, but his journey
thesis is that the engineer in the
future is a builder, someone who decides
what to make and directs AI to make it
rather than writing the code themselves.
So, Deepseek discount is uh permanent. I
already said that. Oh, this I really
like. If you uh just uh
news.google.com/foryou
if you put it in your browser and uh
make it a favorite. Uh this is now my
homepage in in Chrome because I usually
interested in AI and it gives me all the
news about AI and technology. Just very
good way to stay informed. uh KPMG
integrates claude across its core
business. So KPMG is this uh big company
dealing with accounting audits and so on
and uh you see 276,000
employees worldwide now will use uh
Claude and named Antropics preferred
partner for private equity consulting.
So this is also a big thing. Okay. Users
are upset about Gemini 3.5 flash. So
well you know Google this month they had
Google AOR and they many announcements
and one of them is Gemini 3.5 Flash and
they say well intelligence and speed is
awesome amazing incredible
uh but it's been traded uh to maxals uh
for benchmarks and it doesn't really uh
useful in when you work with it uh like
iteratively going back and forth.
Claude actually is very good at that. Uh
but apparently Geminina is not. The
model learned that doing extra stuff
correlates with higher scores. So it
generates that pattern anywhere. So what
it says that it does more than you ask
ask it to do. So it's not exactly what
you're asking it. Okay. This is very
interesting piece of news. Trump
approved Nvidia chip for sale in China,
but Beijing doesn't want it. Nvidia says
it has largely conceded China's AI chip
market to Huawei. So um first there were
restrictions and the Chinese found their
own way to do it and now they have their
own chips and they can do training
cheaper and they don't want American
chips anymore. Okay. MCP tunnels. This
is a very very good idea.
Uh so claude um released managed agents
uh so these are agents which you can
configure on anthropic uh cloud on and
then suppose that this agent it's
running on the cloud but it needs access
to data which is uh locally in your
company behind your firewall like
usually uh how people were solving it
you would expose this data through some
server and then this agent uh or in
entropy cloud has to log into the server
using I don't know username password
some keys or somehow and that means that
you expose your data to outside the idea
of MCP tunnel is that you do it
differently you uh dial out from your
internal uh system and you connect to uh
to cloud uh this way so You keep the
keys inside your company. You don't give
it to external agent. So who initiates
this connection and in this case it's
not agent from outside. It is you
establish this encrypted tunnel. Uh so
that then uh you can use it and uh so
both entropic and openai now have this
uh capability. So uh what you do you
install uh cloud flared. You see blue
install cloud flared and then you create
a tunnel and then from inside your code
you tell it to use this tunnel. It's
really really uh simple. So here you see
actual examples of code. Uh server pi
runs inside your private network. Uh
cloudflared tunnel agent creates
outbound only encrypted connection
and uh yeah that's it. That's it. Uh
okay this is uh about my uh channel. So
we have well I haven't updated these
numbers but uh we have close to 7,000
subscribers and close to 300 videos uh
name of the channel left selector. I
provide uh slides links for the slides
on Google drive and on GitHub under the
video and I usually ask the question and
recently the question uh is like how
which agency you use and how you use
them and what's your experience but
anyway please stop the video and answer
the question. Okay, use cheaper sub
agent models in clo code. Uh in clo code
uh you can use multiple models uh in the
same session. So you can for example use
uh clude oppus for planning and
architecture and you can use clot haiku
for actual execution on simple tasks. So
clot code creates a task list and then
you give it to simpler model to execute
and it doesn't have to be anthropic clot
model. It may be even local model or
deepseek or whatever. You can configure
uh multiple models and here is an
example how to do it. Uh you do pip
install uh light llm proxy and then you
create the yl file where you define
these models. Uh this is how you do
environmental variables. This is uh you
create definitions of your different
agents uh for different models. So this
is uh planner, this is executor and you
see it says the model here it's cloud
opus let's say 4.6 six and here claude
haiku 4.5 and here it's a quen 3 coder
next so it's a Chinese model whatever
and then in your cloud MD you explain
which models to use where and that's it
and then when you start you start with
the planning model with the most uh
smart model and then it will do all this
orchestration uh internally so it's not
difficult to do uh and you can decrease
your cost uh this way Hardness
engineering a system around the model.
Okay, this is generated by probably
Gemini. Okay, tools constraint feedback
loops interfaces instead of observing
over the perfect prompt for uh obsessing
over the perfect prompt. Focus on how
the agent operates over time, what's
allowed to do, how to check its work and
uh how failures are caught and
corrected. Okay, this is the link on
GitHub. practical harness usually
includes. So, it's kind of how to make
your own harness. There are a lot of now
publications and videos on how you can
build your own harness or maybe build it
on top of several harnesses. Uh start
small. Uh each time agent fails, don't
just tweak the prompt. Add a refine the
harness rule tool and so on. Okay. Uh
yeah, here is example. Hermes agent runs
Codex which is open AI and Claude in one
agent. So you you're basically using two
harnesses. Uh demonstrates a
collaborative AI workflow by combining
three top tools. Hermes agent, Codex,
and Claude. ECC everything Claude code.
Very good. It's on GitHub and has
192,000
stars, probably more because this was a
week ago when I looked it up. Uh built
on top of entropic cloud code coding
agent. Uh you see everything clot code
extends clot code with structured skills
usable workflows custom slash commands
and and so on so on repository you see
it's 182 is actually 192 now it's even
more and yeah okay cognition cognition
is a famous company uh they
created Devon which is a coding
assistant uh they never were open source
they were like uh for money for payment
but it's It's good. It's high quality.
And they recently raised 1 billion at 26
billion valuation. So they grew very
fast. The revenue went from 37 million
to almost 500 million in just one year.
And it writes 89% of its own code. So
this is Devon. Okay. Hermes and open
claw. Uh I just provide uh the recent
updates. uh every week you see a lot of
progress, a lot of new features and uh
number of stars uh grows. So it's
172,000 stars for Hermas and 375,000 for
open claw.
Okay. And uh yeah anyway uh next Google
why Google invested 40 billion in
Antropic. So what's what's happening? Um
in April, right, uh Antropic um released
data that their uh subscription rate
increased from 1 billion per year to 9
billion per year in just one year. So
it's a very fast growth.
On April 20th, Amazon uh they didn't
actually wire them the money. They made
a contract on uh compute credits. So for
5 billion with a 20 billion option on
top as you know um um Claude runs on um
uh Amazon cloud on bedrock and uh yeah
so they made a a commitment and then 4
days later Google actually invested real
money $10 billion to Antropic with the
option to another 30 billion um in in
the future. So while why Google uh did
did that because Google has its own
models right it has Gemini models but uh
at the end of the day uh Google makes
money when models run on their
infrastructure right payment for tokens
so with uh running uh claude they maybe
make a smaller portion but Claude now
dominates the market they have 54% of
corporate markets right now Um, OpenAI
used to have something like 70%, now
they're down to 20%. So, Claude is this
big whale and both Amazon and Google,
they trying to be vendors to claude to
get piece of this action,
right? China Deep Seek drops V4 model uh
running on Hi chips completely bypassing
Nvidia. Yeah. And by the way, both
Amazon and Google, they don't use
Nvidia. They have their own chips. Uh uh
Amazon have their own chips. Google have
this TPUs they're uh famous for. Uh
right now Antropic just closed u the
their funding. So I I I said last month
that they closed. No, they didn't close
last last week. Sorry. They only closed
this week. And they uh was supposed to
raise 30 billion. They actually um got
65 billion funding at 900 billion
valuation. Right. So this is the largest
private AI fund raise in history. And
these are the sizes of some of the
biggest companies. You see Nvidia 5
trillion, Alphabet almost five, Apple 4,
Microsoft 3, Meta 1.5, SpaceX 1.5. Well,
they are targeting IPO right now. And
OpenAI is less than a trillion. So
Antropic is now bigger than OpenAI.
Definitely. Uh, next. Uh, oh yeah, this
is from Star Trek. Compassion, that's
the one thing no machine ever had. Maybe
it's the one thing that keeps men ahead
of them. This is yeah, famous quote from
Star Trek. I don't know why I included
it. Okay. Cloud managed agents on
Cloudflare. So, Cloudflare, I use
Cloudflare a lot. This is a very good
service. This is a content management um
content delivery network, CDN. and you
can host your websites and uh there's a
lot of services I I I highly recommend.
So now they have this cloud managed
agents hosted uh the integration uses
cloudflare global network to provide
secure isolated sandboxes. Entropic
describes architecture as decoupling the
brain the agent from the hands the
execution environment running on
cloudflare. Um anyway um Antropic Cloud
and Cloudflare are my two most favorite
tools. So highly recommend to look into
this. Okay. Um Google AI coscientist
and auto research claw. So this is um
about science. So Google published AI
coscientist research in nature. So this
is a paper in nature introducing
hypothesis generation a Gemini power
tool that uses competing AI agents in
idea tournaments to generate and rank
scientific hypothesis inspired by alpha
go agents propose critique and refine
ideas in one Stanford test cos scientist
drug lead reduced uh liver fibrosis
scaring by 91%. So it's a very powerful
way uh to do science and uh auto
research clause self-reinforcing
autonomous research with human AI
collaboration. So it's open source
framework uh Carnegie Melon Google
Stanford US Berkeley. Okay. Uh auto
research claw hosted on GitHub and uh
uses open claw and claw for science.
Yeah, this is very very interesting. uh
deepseek thinking with visual
primitives. So most of the models we're
talking about are language models,
they're thinking in text, but deepseek
actually can think uh in visual uh
primitives. Uh in instead of describing
images using text, the method allows AI
to think using visuals seamlessly handle
tasks like counting, topological
reasoning. Incredibly, this system uses
90% fewer visual tokens than top
commercial models. Okay. Uh, openAI
models solved 80 year old math problem.
So, it is uh disproved in 1946
conjecture by Paul Erdus about planner
unit. Okay. This problem had stood
unsolved for nearly 80 years. The
breakthrough by connecting discrete
geometry with algebraic uh number
theory. two fields which are rarely
bridged. Experts say AI didn't use
exotic math but excels at crossd
disciplinary synthesis finding a path
that human specialists could have
discovered if they like looked at these
two fields at the same time. Okay. Uh
open spec specdriven development
uh well you know what we're doing now.
It used to be that you write the code
and then later you create documentation.
Now it's completely different. You first
create documentation uh you create specs
in a very very detailed and uh
thoughtful manner. You talk to AI back
and forth back and forth creating the
specs and once the specs are created
then AI just writes the code very very
fast. Right? So open spec is open source
specdriven development framework for AI
coding assistance like cloud code and
cursor. Open spec solves a core problem
by of preserving the intent and
requirements. solves the core problem
with the assistant coding intent and
requirements get lost across scattered
chat sessions. Uh so it creates
structured specification files directly
in your repository and and so on. So
these are the directories on openspec
dev, openspec pro and github. Okay,
everything is in plain markdown. So it's
a good thing. Um harnessing llm agents
with skill programs husp
h. So this is paper by NYU and
Salesforce wraps a base LLM in an
external Python control harness converts
passive textual skills into executable
program functions. Uh operating like
physics Maxwell demon uh harness
monitors agent state and then is
failureprone state is detected. Harness
actively intercepts it either overriding
the action or injecting corrective
context. uh test shows this inference
time loop intervention dramatically
boosts accuracy.
So it uh monitors what's happening and
if necessary intervenes like a Maxwell
demon. Okay. AI compute cost exceeded
employee salary. Well, I already spoke
about it but actually corporations
uh are taking action about it. Like for
example, Microsoft recently uh Microsoft
has multiple contracts and licensing
agreements with claude but they started
cancelling most of their direct CL code
licenses and redirecting engineers to
use GitHub copilot CLI. Now GitHub
capilot CLI also has CLA as one of the
models inside it. So they're not really
uh like forbidding using CLA but they're
just forcing to use GitHub. uh cloud
models remain available. Okay. Nvidia
confirmed a similar reality stating that
compute cost on his team is exceeded
employee salaries. Similar with Uber. So
paradox while individual token prices
are going down total bills rise because
AI agents consume more tokens per task.
Goldman Sachs projects a 24fold surge in
token consumption in the next years.
Gardner wants that cheaper tokens won't
necessarily translate into lower
enterprise costs.
Okay. Uh Microsoft Antropic. Microsoft
and Antropic you see they forged the
partnership in November last year which
is about half a year ago and uh Antropic
committed purchasing billions of Azure
compute capacity from Microsoft. Nvidia
joined the deal. Additional hundred uh
10 10 billion investment on product
side. Cloud models were integrated into
GitHub, Copilot, Microsoft 360 CFKA. So
they they continue to cooperate. It's
just that Microsoft trying to save some
money. Uh okay. They also entered talks
into AI chip deal involving Microsoft uh
Maya server chips. Okay. Uh next uh
quantum informed AI for chaotic
processes. So this is interesting. Uh
this is a paper and the idea is uh so
this is University College London that
in certain situations
uh you you have uh data like a quantum
data which is coetic in nature but uh
model can make uh some judgment about
this data with a better accuracy I if it
uh uses quantum as part of the pipeline.
So you see the quantum informed AI can
predict highly chaotic and complex
systems such as weather, turbulence and
disease spread with about 20% greater
accuracy than classical AI. So
interesting. So this is u one one of the
first demonstrations that quantum
calculations can actually help
uh top view agent version two with Cance
uh 20 model from Bance. So you know
Bidance is a huge Chinese company and uh
this model uh is for generating long
form videos. So it comes with different
prices from 0644 $50 per month. And uh
it does like everything scripting voices
images clips editing all together in one
interface. You just talk to it and it
does things for you. Uh yes. Uh next
multiverse computing LLM plus quantum
blocks. So this is parallel to what I
was just talking about. But this is
metal lama model and a small set of
quantum uh blocks like a really small
number of parameters running a hybrid
system on IBM cubit quantum processor
reduced the model perplexity improve may
be modest but it had meaningful real
world effect. The quantum enhanced model
correctly answered astronomy and
biological questions that original llama
model got wrong. So again in same
direction AI will deliver wisdom. This
is interesting. This is from Peter
Dandis. I mentioned him many times. I
recommend you to subscribe to him. So
wisdom is a probabilistic pattern
recognition across vast human
experience.
uh future slim a new benchmark replace
real world events and asks AI to
forecast
90 days ahead. It shows that frontier
models like GPD55 already outperforming
crowd prediction markets. AI can
simulate billions of interventions to
identify optimal outcomes. Uh this
artificial wisdom may matter more than
AGI since intelligence solves problems
while wisdom chooses which problem to
solve. Uh so this is very good um and
group uh ring 2.6 six one trillion
parameter model. So this is uh Chinese
uh designed to execute uh complete
multi-step business workflows without
requiring manual interventions. 262k
token window and these are all the links
and it's available oops uh through open
router. Hold on a second.
Why I cannot do it on the whole screen.
Oh gosh, what's going on?
Okay, this Okay, robots. Um, Boston
Dynamics upgraded their Atlas humanoid
robot so it can now carry 100 pound uh
fridge as you can see and uh Hyundai
plans mass produce and deploy Atlas
units. Uh as you know Atlas was acquired
by Hyundai and uh Unitry introduced the
real-time voicedriven uh motion
generated for its G1 humanoid robots and
so on. Okay. Quantum is breaking
encryption. Uh so this is a paper and
YouTube uh video uh securing electric
cryptocurrencies against quantum
vulnerabilities. A team of Google
researchers demonstrated that a short
algorithm can break a 256 bit elliptic
curve discrete algorithm problem uh
using fewer than uh 1200 logical cubits
and 90 million to 40 gates. Uh yes. So
this uh work on um quantum encryption or
how to break it like
making people paranoid and switching to
a better security in the systems. You
see it urges all vulnerable
cryptocurrency communities to migrate to
postquantum cryptography without delay.
Okay. Um Obsidian for memory rag and
MCP. So, Obsidian stores data as a
directory tree of markdown files. It's
called vault, but it's just a directory
with subdirectories markdown files plus
small amount of up metadata. It's
basically a personal wiki with some
indexing. Each node is a plain MD file,
markdown file. You can mix images, PDFs,
and other arbitrary files in the same
tree. Obsidian adds Obsidian folder at
the root. Uh, no database, no
proprietary format. You can use grab uh
rib grab and so on directly over the
vault uh to search for stuff. Obsidian
uses wiki style links uh between the
files. Uh a vault is a folder and
subfolders. Many people use folders like
docs, projects, attachments. When you
paste or drag and drop image into a
node, Obsidian saves it in the file and
inserts the markdown image link and uh
so on. So it's obsidian is a very very
simple and useful uh paradigum uh to use
uh for your memory for your knowledge
base.
Full text search in the app uses
metadata cache. Uh if an external agent
modifies markdown files obsidian rescans
and uh updates the cache wiki engine you
can have multiple vaults multiple
directories. You can use Google drive to
sync folders across devices. uh these
are community plugins uh to do that. So
this is a very good thing to know and to
use uh Obsidian. Andre Karpath like
famously was recommending Obsidian.
Okay. Medvid.org.
Uh so this is u
uh okay. So uh Matthew Gallagher, a
41-year-old self-taught coder from LA,
launched the GLP weight loss uh uh
telealth platform. So this is uh Medv
and this is the website and why I'm
talking about it because they generating
a lot of money. First year 400 million
in revenue and 65 in net profit and
second year 1.8 8 billion projected and
almost 300 in net profit. So, and this
company is basically run by two people
and uh they're using AI for everything
for customer service, for sales, for
promotions, for advertising.
Uh and yeah, what they're doing is
basically a marketing company. They're
selling product which is a weight loss
product which is in high demand. They
also have some other products uh and
they getting something like 15 or 20% on
top for their sales effort and yeah it's
highly highly profitable. Okay. Uh build
business uh with AI. uh yet another uh
video actually two videos how you build
your business um using AI and I will not
go through this because we already over
time but here for example uh start with
dogs rules skills for agents so you
create your own employees they are
simply agents and agents are defined uh
by MD files and then he has a claw chief
which is the main agent which runs
chrome jobs like every 15 minutes and
then and it does something. So every 15
minutes it wakes up to do something
every night the AI does lead generation
via fire crawl writes CRM Google sheets
and so on so on. Okay. Uh about jobs
Dorsy so his company block so he is
flattening the orc chart going from five
layers to maybe two three layers. He
wants to redefine managers as coaches
overseeing hundreds of people rather
than directive supervisors of small
teams. He already requires all
engineering managers to contribute code
directly. Uh from catastrophic
predictions of white colored job loss
toward viewing AI as productivity
multiplier. So on one side we see that
uh some um tasks are now outsourced to
AI. On the other side, we see a lot of
uh requirements for people who can do AI
and orchestrate AI. Uh so interesting.
Bold CEO Ryan Breastlo has fired entire
HR team
uh for creating problems that didn't
exist. So no HR problems disappeared
when they let them go. This this is him.
In the first quarter of this year, tech
companies laid off 80,000 workers.
Approximately like half of them directly
attributed to AI. Goldman Sachs report
like whatever. Clara cut 700 customer
service jobs replaced with AI. Shopify
whatever many many examples fastest
vanishing roles mid-level managers uh
who deal with scheduling status updates
whatever because it's easy to automate
with AI. junior analysts which is cheap
junior labor and one trick specialists
uh people who do just one uh application
or one platform. So these are uh
professions these are roles which can be
easily outsourced to AI. So recommended
steps list repetitive tasks in your job
which can be outsourced to AI automate
one task to build a skill. So become a
AI specialist yourself. uh position
yourself to deploy AI as a hybrid
worker. So you can do the work but you
can also outsource it to AI and use AI.
Okay, these are uh stats and you see in
May we have uh more layoffs than last
year. Okay, and uh this is me as usual
and thank you